The Practical Pig is a animation film directed by Dick Rickard.
After his two brothers are captured, the third little pig
invents a machine to capture the big bad wolf.
Big Bad Wolf (voice) (uncredited), played by Billy Bletcher.
Fiddler Pig (voice) (uncredited), played by Mary Moder.
Fifer Pig (voice) (uncredited), played by Dorothy Compton.
Practical Pig (voice) (uncredited), played by Pinto Colvig.
(voice) (uncredited), played by Tommy Wiggins.
(voice) (uncredited), played by Tom Buchanan.
The Practical Pig is a Silly Symphonies animated
short film produced by Walt Disney.
It was released on February 24, 1939, and was directed by Dick Rickard.
It was the fourth and final cartoon starring The Three Pigs.
Like its predecessors, The Practical Pig incorporates the
song "Who's Afraid of the Big Bad Wolf?".
Unlike its predecessors however, its title cards labeled it as a standalone Three Little
Pigs cartoon, suggesting that they were to get their own series of cartoons.
It is also the second-to-last Silly Symphony released.
The film explores themes of wolf, pig, kidnapping, spanking, swimming.